<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogs | Chili Pepper Design]]></title>
  <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/blog/categories/blogs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T23:45:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Evan Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy SEO: +2,500% page views from a year of casual blogging?]]></title>
    <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/2010/03/04/easy-seo-2500-page-views-from-a-year-of-casual-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-04T00:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com/2010/03/04/easy-seo-2500-page-views-from-a-year-of-casual-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know, you always read in SEO articles about how important blogging is for increasing traffic. It's one of the top suggestions around for improving a website's search engine juice. Well, I am here to testify that it truly is a great SEO tool.</p>

<p>Granted, the title of this post is hyperbolic link-bait. ;) But it's true nonetheless!</p>

<p>I've had this site, "http://chilipepperdesign.com":http://www.chilipepperdesign.com, up for probably five years now but only as a static portfolio site for most of that time. Then, a year ago, I upgraded the site and added a blog to it. In that year <em><em>my monthly page views have increased 2,500% and the number of monthly visits has gone up 4,400%</em></em>.</p>

<p>I don't claim to be a great blogger. I'm not even a prolific blogger. And I had a <em>very</em> small amount of traffic before, so the percent gain is in some ways exaggerated. But it's still an impressive change to me. The idea that casual blogging can increase traffic even <em>just</em> a 1000% would be impressive! But let's get a little perspective:</p>

<h3>Website Traffic Factors</h3>


<h1>Even though I have few posts, some of them are on very hot topics like Facebook Fan Page design. One single post accounts for a <em>full 1/3</em> of my site's total traffic!</h1>

<h1>I crafted my blog with very "Search Engine Friendly" markup. Without this, a blog is useless.</h1>

<h1>I have not used <em>any</em> paid advertising, or done <em>any link building to speak of</em>. This is purely organic search engine traffic from the blog.</h1>

<h1>My website's traffic was pretty much negligible last year, and that skews the percentages. I'm sure now that I have real traffic my gain next year will be much smaller in terms of percentage.</h1>

<p>So, take from this what you will, but it is a fact: blogging gives search engines what they need - <em>content</em>. When you provide a search engine with content you will be rewarded.</p>

<p>!http://www.chilipepperdesign.com/images/48.jpg!</p>

<p>Happy blogging!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress: A Loop inside of a Loop with working Comments]]></title>
    <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/2009/08/25/wordpress-a-loop-inside-of-a-loop-with-working-comments/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-25T15:32:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com/2009/08/25/wordpress-a-loop-inside-of-a-loop-with-working-comments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was faced with a problem while creating a WordPress theme the other day. I was grouping posts together using a 2.8 "custom taxonomy":http://justintadlock.com/archives/2009/05/06/custom-taxonomies-in-wordpress-28 (which is my new favorite thing in WordPress), and wanted to display a list of all related posts above the Comments template. Basically wanted a small "Loop":http://codex.wordpress.org/The_Loop inside of the main Loop - a loop within a loop.</p>

<p>I found a few pages online which address this, such as "WordPress Loop Inside of a Loop":http://lohmantrading.com/Fourced/2009/08/wordpress-loop-inside-of-a-loop/ and "Calling a WordPress Loop from inside a WordPress Loop":http://www.tyssendesign.com.au/articles/calling-a-wordpress-loop-from-inside-a-wordpress-loop/. The idea is pretty simple, and these techniques work fine most of the time.</p>

<p>Everything looked fine to me, as well, until I hit "Submit Comment" to test it... <em>and the comment appeared on the wrong post</em>.</p>

<p>The problem is that inner loop sets the global <em>$post</em> object to the last item in that loop. The methods <em>the_post()</em> and <em>setup_postdata($post)</em> set up the global variables which are needed by <em>the_permalink()</em>, <em>the_title()</em>, <em>comments_template()</em>, etc. So if you call any of these usual "Loop" methods again AFTER the inner loop, they are operating on the <em>last post in the inner loop</em> instead of the <em>current post in the main loop</em>.</p>

<p>The trick is to save the <em>$post</em> objects before the inner loop and to reset them again after the inner loop. To do this, change the Loop structure to follow this template:</p>

<br />


<p>notextile.. <div><pre><code>$posts = get_posts($wp_query->query);  //get the posts
foreach($posts as $post) :   // cycle through them in the main loop</p>

<pre><code>$currentPost = $post;  // save the current "main loop" post 
setup_postdata($post);  // instantiate the global post variables to the main loop post
the_title();    // use your usual Loop methods 
the_content();

$innerposts = get_posts('order=asc&amp;mytaxonomy=mycustomerterm);  //get the posts from my custom taxonomy
foreach($innerposts as $post) :   // cycle through them in the main loop
    setup_postdata($post);  // instantiate the global post variables to the inner loop post
    the_title();    // the inner loop post's title
endforeach;  // end of inner loop

$post = $currentPost;  // reset the post from the main loop
$id = $post-&gt;ID;  // reset the post from the main loop
comments_template();  // now, the comments for the post in the main loop
</code></pre>

<p>endforeach;  // end of main loop</code></pre></div></p>

<p>p.  Another way to do this might be to NOT set the global variables in the inner loop, thus avoiding this issue with the comments entirely. You would just have to directly access the post variables in the inner loop, i.e. <em>$rel_post->post_title</em> instead of <em>the_title()</em>. It would work for simple things, like the title and slug. Check out "custom select query":http://codex.wordpress.org/Displaying_Posts_Using_a_Custom_Select_Query in the WordPress Codex to figure out how to get all of the fields you need from the DB to use this method.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
