<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SEO | Chili Pepper Design]]></title>
  <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/blog/categories/seo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T12:28:17-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Evan Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy SEO: +2,500% page views from a year of casual blogging?]]></title>
    <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.comeasy-seo-2500-page-views-from-a-year-of-casual-blogging"/>
    <updated>2010-03-04T00:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com./easy-seo-2500-page-views-from-a-year-of-casual-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know, you always read in SEO articles about how important blogging is for increasing traffic. It's one of the top suggestions around for improving a website's search engine juice. Well, I am here to testify that it truly is a great SEO tool.</p>

<p>Granted, the title of this post is hyperbolic link-bait. ;) But it's true nonetheless!</p>

<p>I've had this site, "http://chilipepperdesign.com":http://www.chilipepperdesign.com, up for probably five years now but only as a static portfolio site for most of that time. Then, a year ago, I upgraded the site and added a blog to it. In that year <em><em>my monthly page views have increased 2,500% and the number of monthly visits has gone up 4,400%</em></em>.</p>

<p>I don't claim to be a great blogger. I'm not even a prolific blogger. And I had a <em>very</em> small amount of traffic before, so the percent gain is in some ways exaggerated. But it's still an impressive change to me. The idea that casual blogging can increase traffic even <em>just</em> a 1000% would be impressive! But let's get a little perspective:</p>

<h3>Website Traffic Factors</h3>


<h1>Even though I have few posts, some of them are on very hot topics like Facebook Fan Page design. One single post accounts for a <em>full 1/3</em> of my site's total traffic!</h1>

<h1>I crafted my blog with very "Search Engine Friendly" markup. Without this, a blog is useless.</h1>

<h1>I have not used <em>any</em> paid advertising, or done <em>any link building to speak of</em>. This is purely organic search engine traffic from the blog.</h1>

<h1>My website's traffic was pretty much negligible last year, and that skews the percentages. I'm sure now that I have real traffic my gain next year will be much smaller in terms of percentage.</h1>

<p>So, take from this what you will, but it is a fact: blogging gives search engines what they need - <em>content</em>. When you provide a search engine with content you will be rewarded.</p>

<p>!http://www.chilipepperdesign.com/images/48.jpg!</p>

<p>Happy blogging!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[htaccess 301 Redirects from one URL query string to another]]></title>
    <link href="http://thaddeusmt.github.comhtaccess-query-string-301s"/>
    <updated>2009-02-01T13:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thaddeusmt.github.com./htaccess-query-string-301s</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I was trying to set up a "301 Moved Permanently":http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec10.html#sec10.3 redirect that took one dynamic url and redirected to <em>another</em> dynamic url.</p>

<p>Searching around I found "plenty":http://www.seobook.com/archives/001714.shtml of "tips":http://www.webproworld.com/discussion-forum/73178-how-do-you-301-redirect-dynamic-url-url-question-mark.html on how to redirect from older "ugly" style dynamic urls like "test.php?id=999" to new "clean" dynamic urls like "test/999", but that wasn't exactly what I needed. I needed to go from something like "page.php?id=999" to something like"page.php?id=111". Basically just a parameter substitution.</p>

<p>There are two ways to do 301s in an .htaccess file. One is to do a standard "redirect 301", and the other is to use the Apache <em>mod_rewrite</em> module. For reference, this is what a standard "redirect 301" looks like:</p>

<pre><code>redirect 301 /testpage.htm http://www.example.com/testpage2.php
</code></pre>


<p>This won't work with a dynamic URL like "/testpage.htm?id=blah" though. To handle query strings properly you need to use <em>mod_rewrite</em>. Here is the code that ended up working:</p>

<pre><code># redirect testpage.php?id=string1 to testpage.php?id=string2
RewriteCond %{QUERY_STRING} ^id=string1$ [NC]
RewriteRule testpage http://www.example.com/testpage.php\?id=string2 [L,R=301]
</code></pre>


<p><em>The trick is that the second part of the RewriteRule - the URL to redirect to - is evaluated as a Regular Expression but <em>has a "?" in it</em>. This is a RegEx operator, and will break the command unless it is escaped with a "\".</em></p>

<p>Look close at our destination URL "http://www.example.com/testpage.php<span style="color:#f00; font-weight: bold;">\?</span>id=string2". The URL we actually want to redirect to is "http://www.example.com/testpage.php<span style="color:#f00; font-weight: bold;">?</span>id=string2". Forgetting this one tiny little escape character will blow the whole thing up. :)</p>

<p><em>The dirty details:</em></p>

<p>There are plenty of good resources on mod_rewrite conditionals if you want to learn more, but it basically works like this: Apache looks at the RewriteRule, which is a pair of two Regular Expressions (RegEx): the URL we want to change, and what we want to change it to. If mod_rewrite matches the first RegEx expression then it looks at the RewriteCond to see if it should apply the RewriteRule. In this case we are just looking at the QUERY_STRING (everything after the "?"), and doing a case-insensitive [NC] match for "id=string1". If the RewriteCond is true, then the RewriteRule goes in to effect and "testpage" is redirected to "http://www.example.com/testpage.php\?id=string2". Just don't forget to escape that pesky "?" in the query string!</p>

<p>301 Redirects are an important part of SEO and maintaining search engine rankings, so it's nice to have another trick up your sleeve like this.</p>

<p>Here are some very helpful additional resources to improve your htaccess mod_rewrite-fu:</p>

<ul>
<li>"Basic Guide":http://check-these.info/mod_rewrite-basic.html</li>
<li>"Cheat Sheet":http://www.askapache.com/htaccess/mod_rewrite-variables-cheatsheet.html</li>
<li>"Official Guide":http://askapache.info/trunk/misc/rewriteguide.html</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
